[{"id":1,"question":"Partitioner controls the partitioning of what data?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"final keys","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"final values","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"intermediate keys","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"intermediate values","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":2,"question":"SQL Windowing functions are implemented in Hive using which keywords?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"UNION DISTINCT, RANK","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"OVER, RANK","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"OVER, EXCEPT","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"UNION DISTINCT, RANK","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":3,"question":"Rather than adding a Secondary Sort to a slow Reduce job, it is Hadoop best practice to perform which optimization?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Add a partitioned shuffle to the Map job.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Add a partitioned shuffle to the Reduce job.","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Break the Reduce job into multiple, chained Reduce jobs.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Break the Reduce job into multiple, chained Map jobs.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":4,"question":"Hadoop Auth enforces authentication on protected resources. Once authentication has been established, it sets what type of authenticating cookie?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"encrypted HTTP","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"unsigned HTTP","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"compressed HTTP","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"signed HTTP","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":5,"question":"MapReduce jobs can be written in which language?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Java or Python","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"SQL only","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SQL or Java","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Python or SQL","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":6,"question":"To perform local aggregation of the intermediate outputs, MapReduce users can optionally specify which object?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Reducer","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Combiner","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Mapper","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Counter","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":7,"question":"To verify job status, look for the value `___` in the `___`.","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"SUCCEEDED; syslog","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SUCCEEDED; stdout","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"DONE; syslog","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"DONE; stdout","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":8,"question":"Which line of code implements a Reducer method in MapReduce 2.0?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"public void reduce(Text key, Iterator<IntWritable> values, Context context){…}","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"public static void reduce(Text key, IntWritable[","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"public static void reduce(Text key, Iterator<IntWritable> values, Context context){…}","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"public void reduce(Text key, IntWritable[","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":9,"question":"To get the total number of mapped input records in a map job task, you should review the value of which counter?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"FileInputFormatCounter","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"FileSystemCounter","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"JobCounter","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"TaskCounter (NOT SURE)","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":10,"question":"Hadoop Core supports which CAP capabilities?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"A, P","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"C, A","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"C, P","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"C, A, P","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":11,"question":"What are the primary phases of a Reducer?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"combine, map, and reduce","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"shuffle, sort, and reduce","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"reduce, sort, and combine","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"map, sort, and combine","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":12,"question":"To set up Hadoop workflow with synchronization of data between jobs that process tasks both on disk and in memory, use the `___` service, which is `___`.","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Oozie; open source","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Oozie; commercial software","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Zookeeper; commercial software","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Zookeeper; open source","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":13,"question":"For high availability, use multiple nodes of which type?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"data","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"name","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"memory","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"worker","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":14,"question":"DataNode supports which type of drives?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"hot swappable","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"cold swappable","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"warm swappable","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"non-swappable","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":15,"question":"Which method is used to implement Spark jobs?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"on disk of all workers","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"on disk of the master node","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"in memory of the master node","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"in memory of all workers","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":16,"question":"In a MapReduce job, where does the map() function run?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"on the reducer nodes of the cluster","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"on the data nodes of the cluster (NOT SURE)","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"on the master node of the cluster","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"on every node of the cluster","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":17,"question":"To reference a master file for lookups during Mapping, what type of cache should be used?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"distributed cache","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"local cache","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"partitioned cache","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"cluster cache","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":18,"question":"Skip bad records provides an option where a certain set of bad input records can be skipped when processing what type of data?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"cache inputs","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"reducer inputs","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"intermediate values","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"map inputs","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":19,"question":"Which command imports data to Hadoop from a MySQL database?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"spark import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/spark --username spark --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/spark","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"sqoop import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/sqoop --username sqoop --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/sqoop","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"sqoop import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/sqoop --username sqoop --password sqoop --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/sqoop","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"spark import --connect jdbc:mysql://mysql.example.com/spark --username spark --password spark --warehouse-dir user/hue/oozie/deployments/spark","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":20,"question":"In what form is Reducer output presented?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"compressed (NOT SURE)","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"sorted","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"not sorted","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"encrypted","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":21,"question":"Which library should be used to unit test MapReduce code?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"JUnit","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"XUnit","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"MRUnit","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"HadoopUnit","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":22,"question":"If you started the NameNode, then which kind of user must you be?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"hadoop-user","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"super-user","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"node-user","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"admin-user","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":23,"question":"State _ between the JVMs in a MapReduce job","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"can be configured to be shared","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"is partially shared","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"is shared","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"is not shared (https://www.lynda.com/Hadoop-tutorials/Understanding-Java-virtual-machines-JVMs/191942/369545-4.html)","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":24,"question":"To create a MapReduce job, what should be coded first?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"a static job() method","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a Job class and instance (NOT SURE)","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"a job() method","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a static Job class","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":25,"question":"To connect Hadoop to AWS S3, which client should you use?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"S3A","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"S3N","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"S3","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"the EMR S3","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":26,"question":"HBase works with which type of schema enforcement?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"schema on write","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"no schema","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"external schema","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"schema on read","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":27,"question":"HDFS file are of what type?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"read-write","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"read-only","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"write-only","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"append-only","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":28,"question":"A distributed cache file path can originate from what location?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"hdfs or top","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"http","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"hdfs or http","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"hdfs","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":29,"question":"Which library should you use to perform ETL-type MapReduce jobs?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Hive","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Pig","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Impala","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Mahout","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":30,"question":"What is the output of the Reducer?","code":"`map function processes a certain key-value pair and emits a certain number of key-value pairs and the Reduce function processes values grouped by the same key and emits another set of key-value pairs as output.`","reference":"`map function processes a certain key-value pair and emits a certain number of key-value pairs and the Reduce function processes values grouped by the same key and emits another set of key-value pairs as output.`","choices":[{"text":"a relational table","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"an update to the input file","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a single, combined list","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a set of <key, value> pairs","answer":true,"code":false}]},{"id":31,"question":"To optimize a Mapper, what should you perform first?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"Override the default Partitioner.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Skip bad records.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Break up Mappers that do more than one task into multiple Mappers.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Combine Mappers that do one task into large Mappers.","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":32,"question":"When implemented on a public cloud, with what does Hadoop processing interact?","code":"","reference":"","choices":[{"text":"files in object storage","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"graph data in graph databases","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"relational data in managed RDBMS systems","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"JSON data in NoSQL databases","answer":false,"code":false}]},{"id":33,"question":"In the Hadoop system, what administrative mode is used for maintenance?","code":"### Q34. In what format does RecordWriter write an output file? ### Q35. To what does the Mapper map input key/value pairs? ### Q36. Which Hive query returns the first 1,000 values? ### Q37. To implement high availability, how many instances of the master node should you configure? ### Q38. Hadoop 2.x and later implement which service as the resource coordinator? ### Q39. In MapReduce, **_** have _ ### Q40. What type of software is Hadoop Common? ### Q41. If no reduction is desired, you should set the numbers of _ tasks to zero ### Q42. MapReduce applications use which of these classes to report their statistics? ### Q43. _ is the query language, and _ is storage for NoSQL on Hadoop ### Q44. MapReduce 1.0 _ YARN ### Q45. Which type of Hadoop node executes file system namespace operations like opening, closing, and renaming files and directories? ### Q46. HQL queries produce which job types? ### Q47 Suppose you are trying to finish a Pig script that converts text in the input string to uppercase. What code is needed on line 2 below?     1 data = LOAD '/user/hue/pig/examples/data/midsummer.txt'...     2 ### Q48. In a MapReduce job, which phase runs after the Map phase completes? ### Q49. Where would you configure the size of a block in a Hadoop environment? ### Q50. Hadoop systems are **_** RDBMS systems. ### Q51. Which object can be used to distribute jars or libraries for use in MapReduce tasks? ### Q52. To view the execution details of an Impala query plan, which function would you use ? ### Q53. Which feature is used to roll back a corrupted HDFS instance to a previously known good point in time? ### Q54. Hadoop Common is written in which language? ### Q55. Which file system does Hadoop use for storage? ### Q56. What kind of storage and processing does Hadoop support? ### Q57. Hadoop Common consists of which components? ### Q58. Most Apache Hadoop committers' work is done at which commercial company? ### Q59. To get information about Reducer job runs, which object should be added? ### Q60. After changing the default block size and restarting the cluster, to which data does the new size apply? ### Q61. Which statement should you add to improve the performance of the following query?  SELECT   c.id,   c.name,   c.email_preferences.categories.surveys FROM customers c;  ### Q62. What custom object should you implement to reduce IO in MapReduce? ### Q63. You can optimize Hive queries using which method? ### Q64. If you are processing a single action on each input, what type of job should you create? ### Q65. The simplest possible MapReduce job optimization is to perform which of these actions? ### Q66. When you implement a custom Writable, you must also define which of these object?","reference":"### Q66. When you implement a custom Writable, you must also define which of these object?","choices":[{"text":"data mode","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"safe mode","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"single-user mode","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"pseudo-distributed mode","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"<key, value> pairs","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"keys","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"values","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"<value, key> pairs","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"an average of keys for values","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a sum of keys for values","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a set of intermediate key/value pairs","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"a set of final key/value pairs","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SELECT…WHERE value = 1000","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SELECT … LIMIT 1000","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"SELECT TOP 1000 …","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SELECT MAX 1000…","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"one","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"zero","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"shared","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"two or more (https://data-flair.training/blogs/hadoop-high-availability-tutorial)","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"kubernetes","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"JobManager","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"JobTracker","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"YARN","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"tasks; jobs","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"jobs; activities","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"jobs; tasks","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"activities; tasks","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"database","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"distributed computing framework","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"operating system","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"productivity tool","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"combiner","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"reduce","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"mapper","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"intermediate","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"mapper","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"reducer","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"combiner","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"counter","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"HDFS; HQL","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"HQL; HBase","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"HDFS; SQL","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SQL; HBase","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"does not include","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"is the same thing as","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"includes","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"replaces","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"ControllerNode","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"DataNode","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"MetadataNode","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"NameNode","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Impala","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"MapReduce","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Spark","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Pig","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"as (text:CHAR[]); upper_case = FOREACH data GENERATE org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"as (text:CHARARRAY); upper_case = FOREACH data GENERATE org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"as (text:CHAR[]); upper_case = FOREACH data org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"as (text:CHARARRAY); upper_case = FOREACH data org.apache.pig.piggybank.evaluation.string.UPPER(TEXT);","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Combiner","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"Reducer","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Map2","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Shuffle and Sort","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"dfs.block.size in hdfs-site.xmls","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"orc.write.variable.length.blocks in hive-default.xml","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"mapreduce.job.ubertask.maxbytes in mapred-site.xml","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"hdfs.block.size in hdfs-site.xml","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"replacements for","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"not used with","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"substitutes for","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"additions for","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"distributed cache","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"library manager","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"lookup store","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"registry","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"explain","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"query action","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"detail","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"query plan","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"partitioning","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"snapshot","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"replication","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"high availability","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"C++","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"C","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Haskell","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Java","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"NAS","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"FAT","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"HDFS","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"NFS","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"encrypted","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"verified","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"distributed","answer":true,"code":false},{"text":"remote","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Spark and YARN","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"HDFS and MapReduce","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"HDFS and S3","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Spark and MapReduce","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Cloudera","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Microsoft","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Google","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Amazon","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Reporter","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"IntReadable","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"IntWritable","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Writer","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"all data","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"no data","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"existing data","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"new data","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"GROUP BY","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"FILTER","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SUB-SELECT","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"SORT","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Comparator","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Mapper","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Combiner","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Reducer","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"secondary indices","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"summary statistics","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"column-based statistics","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a primary key index","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"partition-only","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"map-only","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"reduce-only","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"combine-only","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Add more master nodes.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Implement optimized InputSplits.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Add more DataNodes.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"Implement a custom Mapper.","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a sort policy","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a combiner policy","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a compression policy","answer":false,"code":false},{"text":"a filter policy","answer":false,"code":false}]}]